<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>CasteHappy</title>
    <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CasteHappy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:39:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost digital worlds #1 - Brawling in 2010</title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/blogs/digital-worlds-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/blogs/digital-worlds-1/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, I was watching my boyfriend play Animal Crossing on the Switch. He was trying to build the neighborhood from the small beach town where he and his family used to go every summer because his grandparents owned an apartment. He has soooo many childhood memories of that place, and he never shuts up about going back there every time summer gets brought up in a conversation, but after some tough family problems and the passing of his late grandma, I feel like that place has gained a lot more emotional meaning for him.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some time ago, I was watching my boyfriend play Animal Crossing on the Switch.
He was trying to build the neighborhood from the small beach town where he and his family used to go every summer because his grandparents owned an apartment. He has soooo many childhood memories of that place, and he never shuts up about going back there every time summer gets brought up in a conversation, but after some tough family problems and the passing of his late grandma, I feel like that place has gained a lot more emotional meaning for him.</p>
<p>After showing me a bunch of spots on the island, he finished the tour by going to a tiny hill by the beach where he had built a tombstone that had a pine cone next to it. He told me that he used to walk around the neighborhood with his grandma to pick up pine cones and he looks back to that memory so fondly that they became some kind of memento for him.</p>
<p>Took me a bit to process it, but I thought that was such beautiful sight. Made me start thinking about how a digital space could have so much meaning and weight for someone, and how it could also last forever as a time capsule, a snapshot from a specific time in your life than even when lacking the context for their creation, you can&rsquo;t help to put myself in the other person&rsquo;s shoes.</p>
<p>With all of that out of the way, I just finished crying my eyes out after looking at some custom stages from a Super Smash Bros. Brawl save file on a Wii that I repaired today haha.</p>
<p>Super Smash Bros is a very important game series to me (and Brawl was the first one I owned), and I started thinking about how those stages were once a fun creative moment for someone, and that now they&rsquo;re lost forever. I still feel dumb by getting so gloomy about something so minor that even the original creator must have forgotten about, but I feel like sharing these stages with the world even if I&rsquo;m the only one that ever see them.</p>
<p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been really interested on the Wii as a system and I keep buying faulty consoles to repair, so I&rsquo;ll probably find more stages, pictures and replays in the future, can&rsquo;t wait to share them with you!</p>
<p>(Used <a href="https://www.gamebrew.org/wiki/Super_Smash_Bros._Brawl_Stage_Studio_Wii#External_links">Brawl Stage Studio</a> so I could see the stages on my PC)</p>
<p>The original creator of these stages is <strong>Rafa</strong>, he played Brawl around 25 hours and <em>almost</em> completed the Subspace Emisary at 75%, props to you!</p>
<h1 id="stage-1-papadopoulos">Stage 1: PAPADOPOULOS</h1>


<center>
<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="stage1.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    Something something Spanish youtuber, if you know you know. But his is an easy 8/10.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>
</center>

<h1 id="stage-2-nevado">Stage 2: NEVADO</h1>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="stage2.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    I really like how all of his stages are symmetric, but this is a 6/10, too big for such little platforms to fight on!
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<h1 id="stage-3-tonteria">Stage 3: TONTERIA</h1>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="stage3.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    I love this one, getting to the top platform can be tricky and everyone is gonna go up there to get an advantage. 9/10!
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<h1 id="stage-4-saltitos">Stage 4: SALTITOS</h1>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="stage4.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    This is the worst one for sure, but it did make me laugh out loud when I saw the name. It's an inside joke I have with my boyfriend that's a reference to his bird pet jumping on stuff. 4/10...
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<h1 id="stage-5-como-un-balon">Stage 5: COMO UN BALON</h1>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="stage5.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    This one's just confusing. Is this supposed to be some kind of football field? Still a solid stage 7/10.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<p><a href="RafaBrawlStages.zip">Here&rsquo;s a zip file with all 5 stages in case you want to download them</a></p>
<p>And that&rsquo;s all I got for today, hopefully I can come back with more stuff like this, I definitely want to find more lost save files and share anything interesting here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreating the Street Fighter 6 Rank Up! animation </title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/portfolio/SF6RankUp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 22:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/portfolio/SF6RankUp/</guid>
      <description>Last month I uploaded a &amp;ldquo;game show&amp;rdquo; video to Diaphone&amp;rsquo;s channel where he and Jmcrofts had to guess the rank of random players in SF6.
From the beginning I knew I wanted to use the rank up animation from the actual game to reveal the results, but it was pretty much impossible for me to rip the animation, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I would have to get to every single rank myself so I could record every single one, and that&amp;rsquo;s not gonna happen lol.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month I uploaded a &ldquo;game show&rdquo; video to Diaphone&rsquo;s channel where he and Jmcrofts had to guess the rank of random players in SF6.</p>
<p>From the beginning I knew I wanted to use the rank up animation from the actual game to reveal the results, but it was pretty much impossible for me to rip the animation, and I&rsquo;m sure I would have to get to every single rank myself so I could record every single one, and that&rsquo;s not gonna happen lol.</p>
<p>This is what I came up with:</p>


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="rankreveal.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>

<p>It was a lot easier than I thought at first, but I had no idea where to start. As always, my strat for making effects or animations is to just aimlessly mess around until it looks acceptable.</p>
<p>First, I started getting the rank renders from SF6&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.streetfighter.com/6/buckler">Buckler&rsquo;s Bootcamp</a>
I don&rsquo;t know if many people know about this, but you can check your match history from the game, and search for other players&rsquo; stats, matches and whatnot.</p>
<p>This is a .zip with all the .pngs (except Legend rank):
<a href="SF6_Ranks.zip">SF6 Rank renders</a></p>
<p>I recommend using some kind of upscaling tool because the files are very small.</p>
<p>Couldn&rsquo;t find the &ldquo;?&rdquo; icon that appears before getting your first rank, so I just made it myself in Photoshop with the pen tool and a bunch of shapes.
<img loading="lazy" src="interrogante.png" alt="questionmark"  />

Never made lightning animations or anything similar so I just started playing around with a couple of effects in AE until I found <strong>BCC Lens Flare 3D</strong>
You can modify every aspect of the lens flare and the presets are a really good starting point.</p>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="bigbrightamberlight.png"</th>
    <th><img src="bigbrightamberlight_edit.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    BigBrightAmberLight default preset before and after editing some parameters
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="difractiondd.png"</th>
    <th><img src="difractiondd_edit.png"</th>
    <th><img src="difractiondd_edit2.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="3" style="text-align: center">
    DifractionDD default preset before and after editing some parameters
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="digicamsundd.png"</th>
    <th><img src="digicamsundd_edit.gif"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    DigiCamSunDD default preset before and after editing some parameters
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>


<p>Now I just need to animate opacity, scale, position, and some other BBC Lens Flare parameters so it matches the original animation. Also made a mask for the big yellow flare with the shape of the halo (that I added later just by making a shape and adding some blur and glow to it)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="lensflare_anim.gif" alt="lensflare"  />
</p>
<p>Looking good! Only thing left is to add the actual rank renders, and a couple of cool details that make the animation a lot cooler.</p>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="particles.png"</th>
    <th><img src="particles_anim.gif"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    Used the CC Star Burst effect for this, but didn't look how I wanted. I don't know how to achieve the look I was going for yet, but it's a really small part of the animation so it's not a big deal.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>
<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="brokenshape.png"</th>
    <th><img src="brokenshape_anim.gif"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    Made a circle and smashed it to pieces by using the Dispersion effect. This also doesn't look exactly like the original animations, where the triangle shaped pieces get smaller and smaller before they disappear. Couldn't find a parameter that could do what I was looking for, and I didn't want to make every shape one by one so I could achieve the exact effect.  But I think it looks cool anyway.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<p>And here&rsquo;s everything put together:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="finalanim.gif" alt="finalanim"  />
</p>


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="sf6ranks.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>

<p>I&rsquo;m pretty happy with the result, but it&rsquo;s not completely identical to the original animation. Some colors are a bit off, light rays are different, less bright and more subtle. But the goal was never to make a 1:1 remake, and it&rsquo;s perfectly serviceable for the video I was making the animation for.</p>
<p>Maybe in the future I&rsquo;ll try to perfect it but for now it&rsquo;s more than enough.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidechain Compression (Audio Ducking) in Vegas Pro</title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/tutorials/sidechain-compressor-vegas-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 22:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/tutorials/sidechain-compressor-vegas-pro/</guid>
      <description>For a month or two I&amp;rsquo;ve been using sidechain compression in most of the vids I&amp;rsquo;ve edited, the result is super satisfying and lets your music choices shine without having to worry about the voiceover getting completely crushed by the songs.
Just in case you don&amp;rsquo;t know what sidechain compression is, just imagine a regular compressor that gets triggered by the signal of another track. So for example, a music track (B) will get compressed only when the voiceover (A) is playing, and when the voiceover is muted, the music won&amp;rsquo;t get compressed at all.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For a month or two I&rsquo;ve been using sidechain compression in most of the vids I&rsquo;ve edited, the result is super satisfying and lets your music choices shine without having to worry about the voiceover getting completely crushed by the songs.</p>
<p>Just in case you don&rsquo;t know what sidechain compression is, just imagine a regular compressor that gets triggered by the signal of another track. So for example, a music track (B) will get compressed only when the voiceover (A) is playing, and when the voiceover is muted, the music won&rsquo;t get compressed at all.</p>
<p>After some research I could only find a couple of solutions for Vegas Pro, <a href="https://www.vegascreativesoftware.info/us/forum/sidechain-aka-key-in-compression-impossible--83449/#ca488703"><strong>one that is native to the software</strong></a>, but that I really don&rsquo;t trust / I find too much work for such a simple thing. And another one that requires a plugin called <a href="https://www.db-audioware.com/sidechain-compressor"><strong>Sidechain Compressor V2 by dB Audioware</strong></a>, it&rsquo;s 79 bucks, but you can get it <a href="https://audioz.download/software/win/137876-download_db-audioware-sidechain-compressor-v200-ce-vr.html"><em>by other means</em></a>.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s very serviceable, but for some reason it won&rsquo;t ever save changes if you close Vegas Pro, so you have to either save the state of the plugin as a preset before closing the program, or just take a screenshot so you remember next time you open the project.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve also read that you can do this with a FabFilter plugin, but I haven&rsquo;t figure out how yet, and I&rsquo;m honestly fine with the proccess I use now.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-use-the-compressor">How to use the compressor</h2>
<p>The proccess is very straightforward, just create one track that will be used as the trigger for the compressor (voice track), and at least another track that will affected by it (music track, for example), then go to <strong>View &gt; Window &gt; Mixing Console</strong> or just press <strong>Ctrl+Alt+5</strong> to open the <strong>Mixing Console</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/mixing_console.png" alt="mixing console 1"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/mixing_console2.png" alt="mixing console 2"  />
</p>
<p>In the Mixing Console, you have to create 2 Buses (A and B) by clicking on <strong>Insert Bus</strong>, and then clicking on the <strong>FX</strong> icon to open the effects list. Search for the Sidechain Compressor V2 plugin and <strong>add it to both buses</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/mixing_console3.png" alt="mixing console 3"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/mixing_console4.png" alt="mixing console 4"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/mixing_console5.png" alt="mixing console 5"  />
</p>
<p>Before doing anything with the compressor, we need to &ldquo;assign&rdquo; the buses to the different tracks we want for this effect.
<strong>We will assign &ldquo;Bus A&rdquo; to the tracks that will trigger the compressor, and &ldquo;Bus B&rdquo; to the tracks that will be affected by the compressor</strong>. In this example, we want the voiceover in Bus A, and the music in Bus B, you can assign the buses by just clicking in the &ldquo;output&rdquo; option (by default this option will be &ldquo;Master&rdquo;).</p>


<div align="center">
<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="/images/mixing_console6.png"</th>
    <th><img src="/images/mixing_console7.png"</th>
  </tr>
</table>
</div>

  
<p>Now, in the compressor, we have to turn on <strong>&ldquo;Universal Sidechain&rdquo;</strong> in both Buses. Then we just have to set Bus A to <strong>&ldquo;Send&rdquo;</strong> and Bus B to <strong>&ldquo;Receive&rdquo;</strong>.</p>


<div align="center">
<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="/images/mixing_consoleA.png"</th>
    <th><img src="/images/mixing_consoleB.png"</th>
  </tr>
</table>
</div>
  
<p>And that&rsquo;s basically all there is to it, only thing left is to tweak stuff around <strong>but you only want to modify the compressor in Bus B, the compressor we added to Bus A is just to send the signal to Bus B</strong></p>
<p>I won&rsquo;t explain all the knobs and options in the compressor, you can look everything up in google, there&rsquo;s a lot of information on compressors and what all the settings and options are. I&rsquo;ll just leave you with a quick example of how the final result sounds like.</p>
<p>Parameters I&rsquo;ve changed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Threshold: -26</li>
<li>Ratio: 10:1</li>
<li>Release: 1000ms</li>
</ul>
<audio controls preload="auto">
    <source src="/audio/compressor.wav">
</audio>

<p>This is how it sounds without the compressor:</p>
<audio controls preload="auto">
    <source src="/audio/no-compressor.wav">
</audio>

<p>Obviously the music eats up the voiceover, so we&rsquo;d have to lower the music much more than that.
This way, the music will be too low or too high sometimes unless we manually increase or decrease the levels when we need it, which is a lot more work than using the compressor to do everything for us.</p>
<audio controls preload="auto">
    <source src="/audio/no-compressor-lower.wav">
</audio>

<p>Of course there&rsquo;s a lot more to this and I&rsquo;m still a noob at everything related to audio.</p>
<p>The results will be a lot better using Equalizers and a bunch of other effects, but just by using audio ducking you have a lot more freedom to choose different kind of songs for the project and overall the video will flow a lot better because you won&rsquo;t have to be as careful with the voice track being too loud / quiet.</p>
<p>I hope this helps someone, I&rsquo;ve found a bunch of people mentioning this plugin in a couple of forums but I haven&rsquo;t seen any visual guides for it.</p>
<p>If you have any questions let me know in the comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 1st post</title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/page/</guid>
      <description>Desc Text.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fake zoom out transition with SF6&#39;s animations</title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/tutorials/fakezoomout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/tutorials/fakezoomout/</guid>
      <description>I was asked by ytrilogy1091 about how I made this transition from one of the latest videos I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded to Diaphone&amp;rsquo;s channel:
Your browser does not support the video tag. This is the actual question:
Everything in the foreground I made it myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about the &amp;ldquo;rank reveal&amp;rdquo; animation in this post.
For the zoom out animation, I just needed 2 files, a still image of the garage door background that appears when choosing characters, and a video of the transition that plays between choosing a stage and going to character select.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was asked by <strong>ytrilogy1091</strong> about how I made this transition from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmHg8T8IMuw">one of the latest videos I&rsquo;ve uploaded to Diaphone&rsquo;s channel</a>:</p>


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="transition1.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>

<p>This is the actual question:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="ytcomment.png" alt="comment"  />
</p>
<p>Everything in the foreground I made it myself, I&rsquo;ve already talked about the &ldquo;rank reveal&rdquo; animation <a href="/portfolio/SF6RankUp/">in this post</a>.</p>
<p>For the zoom out animation, I just needed 2 files, a still image of the garage door background that appears when choosing characters, and a video of the transition that plays between choosing a stage and going to character select.</p>
<p>For the screnshot I disabled the HUD and used a free camera mod to get closer to the actual door so I could use it by itself as a transition (closing the door) without having to zoom in and losing quality.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="garagedoor.png" alt="garagedoor"  />
</p>
<p>The video is not modified at all, I only disabled the HUD and just let it play until the characters show up</p>


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="animation1.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>

<h1 id="step-1-separate-the-2-parts-of-the-animation">Step 1: Separate the 2 parts of the animation</h1>
<p>So the first step is to reverse the video clip so it starts at the garage door, and ends at the long hallway with neon lights.
If you&rsquo;ve noticed, there isn&rsquo;t really a smooth transition from the hallway to the character select garage door, but the in-game graphics hide it really well, and that&rsquo;s kind of the secret of the transtion.</p>
<p>So after reversing the clip, I cut it into 2 different tracks, one for the zoom animation (Track 2), and one for the hallway animation (Track 1).</p>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th>
    <video width=100% controls>
        <source src="step1.webm" type="video/webm">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.  
    </video>
    </th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    I scaled up the first clip so it exactly matches the size of the screenshot, but it's irrelevant for the effect we want.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<p>The problem here is that the hallway animation always moves at the same speed, so I&rsquo;ll need to fake the movement so it matches the speed of the zoom out of the first clip.</p>
<h1 id="step-2-position-the-clips-correctly">Step 2: Position the clips correctly</h1>
<p>Now I need to align the position of both clips. As you maybe have noticed, the perspective makes it so the end of the first clip and the end of the second one, don&rsquo;t match at all. The scale is also completely off.</p>


<center>
<table>
  <tr>
    <th><img src="perspective.png"</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    "X" is the center of the image, the red line is where the floor starts.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>
</center>

<p>So I&rsquo;m gonna change the position and scale of the clip on track 1, so I get similar looking frames. Doesn&rsquo;t have to perfectly match.</p>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th>
    <video width=100% controls>
        <source src="comparison.webm" type="video/webm">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.  
    </video>
    </th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    A good visual reference is the size of the neon lights in both frames
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<p>So now it&rsquo;s looking like this:


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="step2.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>
</p>
<h1 id="step-3-the-actual-zoom-out">Step 3: The actual zoom out</h1>
<p>At this point, the last step is to fake the movement of the second clip so it matches the speed of the zoom out animation of the first one.
We can get this done with a simple scale animation.</p>
<p>Right now the scale value of the hallway clip is 300%, I&rsquo;ll add a keyframe at the very first frame (300%), and another one 35 frames later with a value of 113%.
Keyframe velocity is really important here, I&rsquo;ll make it so it starts scaling down really fast, but smoothly stops at the end.</p>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th>
    <video width=100% controls>
        <source src="zoomout1.webm" type="video/webm">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.  
    </video>
    </th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    Included how the velocity curve looks like just in case it's helpful.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<p>And that&rsquo;s pretty much it, now if you play the full clip it looks pretty convincing.</p>


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="zoomout2.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>

<p>If it looks off, just play around with the distance between the 2 keyframes and the velocity curves until it looks somewhat seamless.</p>
<h1 id="step-4-hide-in-plain-sight">Step 4: Hide in plain sight</h1>
<p>The only thing left to do now is to <strong>lie</strong> in order to better sell the effect. I added a third track for the still image of the garage door, and animated its opacity so it transitions into the first clip.</p>


<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="step4-1.webm" type="video/webm">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>

<p>Then I added a fourth track with an adjustment layer, so I could add a Zoom blur effect that starts and ends at the same time as the actual &ldquo;zoom out&rdquo; we stitched together.</p>


<table>
  <tr>
    <th>
    <video width=100% controls>
        <source src="step4-2.webm" type="video/webm">
        Your browser does not support the video tag.  
    </video>
    </th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2" style="text-align: center">
    This zoom effect also hides any imperfection, like the awful quality at the start of the second clip for example. Or any possible misalignments.
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<p>And that&rsquo;s the final result, this is how the actual timeline looks like:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="timeline.png" alt="timeline"  />
</p>
<p>As I said at the beginning, this is actually a really simple and common transition that sadly a lot of people overuse and spam at every opportunity they get lol (I used to be guilty of this as well), but this is the actual solution for getting the effect to look smooth and somewhat convincing.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not used to making tutorials and English is not my first language so sorry if this was too much, or a bit confusing. Tried to explain it for someone that&rsquo;s a beginner.
Also you can just follow the exact same steps in every editing software if you understand how it works.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cool Stuff</title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/links/</guid>
      <description> Vimm&amp;rsquo;s lair EdgeEmulation The Gay Gamer La era del videojuego Imaginarysong UnderRealLife BeetBeatBit MartinFX Glenn Chan The Brawl Compendium Dustloop thx nightcore MMaker TekkenNotationMaker HackMii WiiBrew Wii Drive Chip Database </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="https://vimm.net/">Vimm&rsquo;s lair</a></li>
<li><a href="https://edgeemu.net/">EdgeEmulation</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thegaygamer.com/">The Gay Gamer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://laeradelvideojuego.wordpress.com/">La era del videojuego</a></li>
<li><a href="https://imaginarysong.medium.com/">Imaginarysong</a></li>
<li><a href="https://underreallife.neocities.org/">UnderRealLife</a></li>
<li><a href="http://beetbeatbit.blogspot.com/">BeetBeatBit</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ratinfx.github.io/">MartinFX</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.glennchan.info/">Glenn Chan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1yYjA4_OPQZcR_YaEVfGzFs7NHC1nFl07L9N4f6_HTSc">The Brawl Compendium</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.dustloop.com">Dustloop</a></li>
<li><a href="https://thx.nightcore.pl/">thx nightcore</a></li>
<li><a href="https://mmaker.moe/">MMaker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://frostemanneogard.github.io/TekkenNotationMaker/">TekkenNotationMaker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hackmii.com/">HackMii</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wiibrew.org">WiiBrew</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.wiidrives.com">Wii Drive Chip Database</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s this?</title>
      <link>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CasteHappy.github.io/TheDoorOfFate/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m Caste, a self-taught video editor and fighting game competitor since around 2008. From the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve had internet access I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really fascinated by video editing and graphic design, thanks to places like Emudesc (a now defunct internet forum about videogames), DeviantArt, and of course Youtube and the YTP / YTPMV community, which really got me into learning proper video editing software and sparked my interest for a lot of internet subcultures and their repective styles, music preferences, and of course their sense of humour (I&amp;rsquo;ve been here for the laughs from the beginning, you see?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="hey">Hey!</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m Caste, a self-taught video editor and fighting game competitor since around 2008. From the first time I&rsquo;ve had internet access I&rsquo;ve always been really fascinated by video editing and graphic design, thanks to places like <strong>Emudesc</strong> (a now defunct internet forum about videogames), <strong>DeviantArt</strong>, and of course <strong>Youtube</strong> and the <strong>YTP / YTPMV</strong> community, which really got me into learning proper video editing software and sparked my interest for a lot of internet subcultures and their repective styles, music preferences, and of course their sense of humour (I&rsquo;ve been here for the laughs from the beginning, you see?).</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been a really slow learning process because I&rsquo;ve never seen any of this as a professional skill, and I honestly used it as a last resort when the Covid pandemic hit. Since 2020 I&rsquo;ve probably learned a lot more than in the last decade, and there&rsquo;s still a lot I have to explore and get good at.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="video-editing">Video Editing</h2>
<p>These are the main tools I use:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>MAGIX Vegas Pro 21</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adobe After Effects 2021</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adobe Photoshop 2021</strong></li>
<li><strong>Reaper</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>I also have experience with <strong>Adobe Premiere</strong> but I GREATLY dislike the workflow, and the advantages from Vegas Pro are not worth it.</p>
<p>Since August 2020 I&rsquo;ve been working mainly as a video editor for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Diaphone"><strong>Diaphone</strong></a> (a top level fighting game player and content creator), making mostly all videos and thumbnails on the channel (around 185) and getting over 6 Million views and 70.000 suscribers. While also making some other videos and thumbnails for other smallers creators in the same space.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83ZaF5MCVug&amp;list=PLVMomAI1oadE7rru_EC7aDWWqTuectgrt&amp;ab_channel=Diaphone"><strong>Playlist with all the vids I&rsquo;ve edited</strong></a></p>
<p>Outside of work I&rsquo;m a YTPMV / 音 MAD enthusiast and I make them from time to time, which is my favourite audiovisual genre and internet culture.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve participated in some YTPMV Collaborations, including the almost 2 hour long <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K5zzrjKrCdc"><strong>&ldquo;The hhgregg Collab - It&rsquo;s &ldquo;Christmas in July!&rdquo;</strong></a>, with entries from around 50 people.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SZnHzeT_8_o&amp;list=PLVMomAI1oadFF5NCQUlpiXDABtrIsue4h&amp;ab_channel=CasteHappy"><strong>Playlist with all the YTPMVs I&rsquo;ve made</strong></a></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="competitive-gaming">Competitive gaming</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been competing and organizing tournaments for SSB (and much later, fighting games) since around 2009 - 2010, getting repectable placements in Smash 4, Smash Ultimate, Dragon Ball FighterZ and Guilty Gear Strive.
Back in 2018 I even got sponsored by &ldquo;Vortex&rdquo;, a now defunct local fgc team, but it didn&rsquo;t last very long. I also got into speedrunning around 2017.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>#22 Smash 4 Spanish Ranking (2015)</strong></li>
<li><strong>Best Smash 4 player in Albacete (2014 to 2016)</strong></li>
<li><strong>Best Smash Ult. player in Albacete (2019)</strong></li>
<li><strong>#39 Dragon Ball FighterZ Spanish Ranking (2019)</strong></li>
<li><strong>#3 Road to Red Bull Gladiators Eur. classifier (Guilty Gear Strive)</strong></li>
<li><strong>Multiple Top 8 results in locals around Spain</strong></li>
<li><strong>Former WR for SSBB Classic Mode (05:25) - 03/03/2017</strong></li>
<li><strong>24th out of 231 in Shovel Knight Any% (47:52) - 23/01/2020</strong></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="other-interests">Other interests</h2>
<p>Besides all that, I&rsquo;m into videogames (who would&rsquo;ve thought) and videogame criticism. Same with music, but I&rsquo;ve been less and less interested in new music for a couple of years now. I have a <a href="https://www.backloggd.com/u/CasteHappy/"><strong>Backloggd</strong></a> and <a href="https://rateyourmusic.com/~CasteHappy"><strong>RateYourMusic</strong></a> account if you wanna see what I&rsquo;ve been up to.</p>
<p>As of late I&rsquo;ve gotten into console repairs (mostly Wii), which I always liked but found a bit inaccessible until now.
I&rsquo;m also the biggest advocate for videogame piracy, so I really enjoy learning about modding and homebrew.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
